Personal Information

Name Alexander Toschev

Passport Russia

Date of birth 17 May 1989

Contacts atoschev@kpfu.ru (preferred), sanchis.no@gmail.com

Research Gate https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Alexander_Toschev3

Personal Blog http://toschev.me

Personal Profile

Strengths Excellent *Team Player*, collaborative with colleagues very good at avoid

with colleagues, very good at avoiding and managing conflicts; good in sharing knowledge; good motivator; passionate and curious; motivated in self-improving; striving for excellence in all its aspects; good ability in communication; proactive and self-driven; precise and meticulous; energetic; non conventional thinking is appreciated

Weaknesses

Problems when working in *strict* not-understandable rules; problems when only working on repetitive and not creative tasks; frustrated when forced to maximize quantity and not quality; might show frustration if isolated for too long; might suffer in environments with low level of organization; non conventional thinking is appreciated

Computing Professional Experience

current Software and solution Team lead in ICL services (formerly known as Fujitsu GDC Russia), Kazan, Russian Federation.

Retail software and hardware development and design

current Phd student at Kazan Federal University, Kazan, Russian Federation, Kazan,

Russian Federation.

Cognition framework development

Software and solution Architect in ICL Services (formerly known as Fujitsu GDC Russia, Distributed retail system development.

2009 Software and solution Developer in ICL Services (formerly known as Fujitsu GDC Russia), Distributed logistic system development.

Education Background

Master degree in computer science, Kazan Federal University, Russia, Faculty of calculated mathematics and cybernetics, Thesis: Intelligent automation system for incident solving.

2011 Professional translator, Kazan Federal University, Russia, Faculty of linguistic.

2015 **Phd degree in computer science**, *Kazan Federal University, Russia*, Faculty of computer system, Planned on December 2015.

Teaching Experience

2012-Now,

Software Architecture

Kazan Federal

University

University

2012-Now, Kazan Federal Object Oriented Programming

Projects

Thinking-Understanding Intelligent system for automatic incident processing

(2012-now)

Singularity 3D game engine on DirectX 7 with programming shaders in C++

(2010)

Menta Automatic application construction via Natural Language processing

IDP Semantic Document Processing

Cybervisor Data flow integration with several systems written in C++

Language Competence

Russian mother language English Technical: good;

Written: good; Spoken: good

Professional Training

2015 Communication Skills

2009 Software Architect

2008 OpenMP and Intel MPI development

Computing Knowledge

Operating Microsoft Windows, Linux, Mac OS Programming C++, C#, Java, Scala, VB, Delphi,

Systems Pascal, VB.NET, T-SQL

Databases SQL, JDBC, DB2, Access, Post- Web Publishing HTML, XML, JavaScript, jQuery

greSQL, Neo4j, HypergraphDB

Software Design UML, Problem Frames Tools Word, PowerPoint, Excel, Outlook,

Visio, Dream weaver, ArgoUML, Vi-

Specification sual Paradigm

Profiles VisualVM, .NET Profiler Unmanaged Code Analyst profiler

Journal papers

Toshchev A., Talanov M. - Computational emotional thinking and virtual neurotransmitters, International Journal of Synthetic Emotions (IJSE), 2014, 05/2014

Toshchev A., Talanov M. - Coping and High Level Emotions Aspects of Computational Emotional Thinking, International Journal of Synthetic Emotions (IJSE) 2015, 06/2015

Conferences and Workshops

Toshchev A., Talanov M. - Thinking Lifecycle as an Implementation of Machine Understanding in Software Maintenance Automation Domain, Agent and Multi- Agent Systems: Technologies and Applications: 9th KES International Confer- ence, KES-AMSTA 2015 Sorrento, Italy, June 2015, Proceedings (Smart Innovation, Systems and Technologies), Sorento, Italy, 2015

Toshchev A. - Thinking model and machine understanding in automated user request processing, CEUR Workshop Proceedings (RCDL-2014), Dubna, Russia, 2014

Toshchev A. Talanov M. - ARCHITECTURE AND REALIZATION OF IN- TELLECTUAL AGENT FOR AUTOMATIC INCIDENT PROCESSING US- ING THE ARTIFICIAL INTEL-LIGENCE AND SEMANTIC NETWORKS, Electronic libraries , Kazan, Russia, 2014

Toshchev A. Talanov M. Krehov A. Khasianov A. - *Thinking-Understanding approach in IT maintenance domain automation*, Global Journal on Technology (WCIT-2012) , Barcelona, Spain, 2012

Conference and Workshop Activities

2012 WCIT

2014 RCDL

2013 AINL

2015 AMSTA